Scull Family
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Scull family scrapbook
1953-1996
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Scull family
1 volume, circa 300 items on 1 microfilm reel.
The Scull family scrapbook dates from 1953-1996 and comprises approximately 300 items including photographs, newspaper and magazine clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and other printed material regarding the artwork and public appearances of Haydée, Sahara, and Michael Scull.
Biographical Note
Twin sisters Haydée and Sahara Scull were born in Havana, Cuba, and studied painting and sculpture at the Escuela de Bellas Artes de San Alejandro in Havana. They are best known for their humorous three-dimensional paintings and sculptures of Old Havana and trendy South Beach. Haydée's son Michael, born in 1953, collaborated with his mother and aunt as a teenager. He left Cuba in 1967 to study art in Canada, and subsequently settled in Miami. In 1969 Haydée and her daughter Elizabeth (born 1957) joined Michael in Miami and in 1973 Sahara left Cuba for Miami. They established their permanent residence and studio in the art deco district of Miami Beach. Most of their work is commissioned for private collections.
Scope and Content Note
This small collection provides scattered documentation regarding the art and public appearances of Haydée, Sahara, and Michael Scull. The collection comprises a scrapbook, and a small amount of related unbound material, including photographs, news clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, and other printed material.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as two series:
Series 1: Scrapbook, circa 1983-1996
Series 2: Unbound Materials, 1953-1996, undated
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms.
Subjects:
Scull, Sahara; Scull, Michael, 1953-; Scull, Haydée
Subjects-Topical:
Painters -- Florida -- Miami; Sculptors -- Florida -- Miami; Assemblage (Art); Cuban Americans -- Florida -- Miami; Cuban American art; Cuban American artists; Artists -- Florida -- Miami
Types of Materials:
Scrapbooks; Photographs; Works of art
Names:
Scull, Sahara; Scull, Michael, 1953-; Scull, Haydée
Provenance
The collection was loaned to the Archives of American Art for microfilming in 1997 by Haydée and Sahara Scull and returned to them after filming.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available only on microfilm reel 5142. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Scrapbook, circa 1983-1996, Series 1:
  The scrapbook contains photograps of the Sculls and others, printed material such as exhibition announcements and catalogs, and several letters. The material relates to the Scull family and other Cuban American and Hispanic artists.
  - Scrapbook, circa 1983-1996 (Reel 5142)
- Unbound Materials, 1953-1996, undated, Series 2:
  Unbound material consists of the same type of documentation found in the scrapbook and includes résumés of the Scull family, photographs, letters, and printed material.
  - Biographical Material, 1992-1993, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Letters, 1985-1996 (Reel 5142)
  - Artwork by Sandra L. Russell, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Photographs of Haydée, Sahara, and Michael Scull, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Photographs of Billboards Advertisements with Haydée and Sahara Scull, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Photographs of Artwork by the Sculls, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Clippings, 1953, 1987, 1990-1995, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1985-1993, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Artwork by the Sculls, undated (Reel 5142)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1985-1995 (Reel 5142)